<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>To the right honorable the knights, citizens, and burgesses in Parliament assembled. Reasons humbly offer'd by Captain George St. Lo, for bringing down the exorbitant rates of seamens wages from 50 s. and 3 l. a month, to 30 s. and 35 s. a month.</title>
            <author>St. Lo, George, d. 1718.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B32620</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99886589</idno>
  <idno type="VID">187479</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240899865</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 816.m.7[51]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R226249</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99886589</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99886589e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B32620)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 187479)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C8:1[53])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>To the right honorable the knights, citizens, and burgesses in Parliament assembled. Reasons humbly offer'd by Captain George St. Lo, for bringing down the exorbitant rates of seamens wages from 50 s. and 3 l. a month, to 30 s. and 35 s. a month.</title>
                  <author>St. Lo, George, d. 1718.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1694?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Publication information from the British Library.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="corporate_name">England and Wales. --  Royal Navy --  Pay, allowances, etc. --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Sailors --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-11 </date>
            <label>Maria Cecilia Caride </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-11 </date>
            <label>Maria Cecilia Caride</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="document">
            <pb facs="tcp:187479:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:187479:1"/>
            <head>To the Right Honorable THE <hi>Knights, Citizens, and Burgesses</hi> In PARLIAMENT Assembled.</head>
            <head type="sub">Reasons humbly Offer'd by Captain <hi>George St. Lo,</hi> for bringing down the Exorbitant Rates of Seamens Wages from <hi>50 s.</hi> and <hi>3 l.</hi> a Month, to <hi>30 s.</hi> and <hi>35 s.</hi> a Month.</head>
            <p>THE Seamen for the lucre of such great Wages in Merchant-Men, do lurk and hide themselves from their Majesties Service, whereby it comes to be so difficult to get Men for the Kings Ships; whereas if their Wages were near alike, their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesties would never want Seamen in their Fleet. A Seamans Wages, in a Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chant-man, in time of Peace, is usually about 25 <hi>s.</hi> a Month, and in a Collier 30 or 40 <hi>s.</hi> a Voyage, which now is come to 6, 7, and 8 <hi>l.</hi> a Voyage; and 50 <hi>s.</hi> and 3 <hi>l.</hi> a Month in a Merchant-man, which while they can have, they will leave their Majesties Ships and abscond themselves from being Imprest, rather than serve for the usual Rate of the Navy, which is 23 <hi>s.</hi> a Month at 28 days in a Month, which is 25 <hi>s.</hi> a Month at twelve Months in the Year; and till such their extraordinary Wages be brought down, it is not to be thought it will be otherwise, though it is not evident they are ever the Richer at the Years End for any such large Wages.</p>
            <p>Therefore it is humbly proposed, that for their Majesties Service, the Rates of Seamens Wages in Merchant-men be reduced to 30 <hi>s. per</hi> Month going with Convoy, and 35 <hi>s. per</hi> Month running without Convoy; and that if any private Sailer shall demand more, than the Rates aforesaid, that he may be brought to an Office to be erected for Registring of Shipping and small Craft, and thence sent on Board one of their Majesties Ships of War, there to serve for a Year as a Prest-man.</p>
            <p>☞ This will be an Equivalent for the Masters and Owners of Ships, providing a Seaman according to my Proposal; for Example, a Ship of 70 Tun hath seven Men to Sail her, whereof five are before the Mast, and now receive 50 <hi>s.</hi> a Month: By this Regula<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion the Master will save 5 <hi>l.</hi> a Month while at Sea, in lieu of one Seaman each Ship is to find for the King, and hereby the Seamen in their Majesties Ships will have Encourage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, because they will have Mony given them to go, and lose none of the great Wages which now tempts them to lurk, and go in Merchant-men.</p>
            <p>It may be Objected, that this Reducement of Wages will make Seamen leave their native Country, and go into Foreign Service.</p>
            <p>To which it is Answered on the contrary, that they will not do it, because first no Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion Victuals so well as the <hi>English,</hi> and our Sailers love to Eat well: I that have Summer'd and Winter'd them so often, know something of their Tempers; Secondly, It is as good Wages, if not better, than any other Country gives; and therefore it is not to be thought, that <hi>English</hi> Seamen (except some few Scoundrels, I have observed good for nothing) will leave their Native Country, their Friends and their Families to go into Foreign Service for the same or less Wages, which may sufficiently be seen by their refusing the <hi>French</hi> Service, tho they had large offers made them.</p>
            <p>☞ This done, will be a vast Advantage to their Majesties Fleet, and the Benefit of Trade; 'twill be an Ease on all sides, and make Seamen plenty.</p>
            <p>And to shew that there are <hi>English</hi> Seamen sufficient both for publick and private Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice, we may observe this last Summer, that their Majesties Fleet was very well Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned, besides great Fleets of Merchant Ships, both Abroad and at Home: and if Care in the first place be taken of the Grand Fleet, which is the main Interest of the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, the Seamen for Merchants Ships may be the least of Our Care, for they will not fail of having Men enough.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>